Product Management | Strategy | Innovation

+1 (215) 252-6186 | mail@vidurbhatnagar.com | www.vidurbhatnagar.com

SUMMARY

Award-winning technical product manager, with a successful record of delivering consumer and enterprise products, including at my own healthcare startup. Experienced in customer discovery, analytics, UI/UX, crafting product vision, strategy, along with leading cross-functional teams through ideation, development & launch.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SLALOM LLC

Product Management Lead (Global Data & Analytics)

JAN 2019 - SEP 2019

First hire in a new team established to develop SaaS products at a consulting firm and help global teams scale delivery.

- Led a cross-functional team of data scientists and engineers to **launch a new sales intelligence tool across 5 markets** while conducting user interviews, translating business requirements to technical features and coaching the team on agile delivery.
- Architected a data platform for data ingestion and reporting from multiple sources at SightLife (Slalom's largest non-profit client), where I was **selected in a team of 6 across 300 applicants.**

KERITON LLC

Founder & CEO MAR 2016 - AUG 2018

Launched Keriton while pursuing MS in Robotics at UPenn (on a hackathon winning idea) to help moms, nurses and lactation consultants achieve better outcomes for babies by automating breastmilk management. Eventually, took a leave of absence to run the company full-time as I was granted **extraordinary skills status by the US government** (O1 Visa, EB1 Green Card).

- Raised \$1.6M from top-tier VCs and strategic partners like DreamIt, Penn Medicine, International Blue Cross, etc.
- Conducted design thinking sessions with 25 nurses and 350+ moms to launch a 2-app system which **prevented \$2.5M in HIPAA-errors** at a single site, **decreased expiration of milk by 50%** and **saved nurses' time by 50%**.
- Designed UI mockups for 40+ screens and crafted exceptional user experiences such as the world's first lactation analytics platform with real-time chat and photo-sharing, **helping moms' increase their pumping by 40%**.
- Managed the technology team and architected the SaaS platform 2 apps, 4 products, 40+ workflows, 60+ database tables/views, and 80+ APIs with **zero downtime in 1.5 years** with 99.99% SLAs.
- Closed \$1.1M worth of multi-year B2B contracts, created pre-sales collateral and conducted sales demos.
- Coordinated multiple go-live activities at customers' end, and in one instance trained 150+ nurses in 2 weeks.
- Pitched at numerous events to win 14 national and international awards like Gold Stevie Startup of the Year, America's
 Most Unique Small Business, Impact Pediatric SXSW Pitch Competition, etc., resulting in 30+ organic press articles.

SAP LABS INDIA

Product Owner & Software Engineer

FEB 2013 - JUL 2015

- As the Youngest Product Owner (globally), I led the charge on enterprise visualizations & dashboards for SAP Cloud for Planning and SAP Lumira. I was responsible for defining roadmaps, building cross-functional consensus, and delivery.
- Created user stories and conducted customer workshops as a **Product Management Fellow for SAP Palo Alto team** for Stanford's Social Flex Seating a group-ticketing app.
- Selected as a Technical Fellow in the Managing Director's office to develop API services, SQL scripts, and predictive
 algorithms on SAP HANA (SAP Sports Analytics) that helped a Cricket franchisee in India win back to back championships.
- Developed a novel algorithm for SAP HANA to optimize compression algorithms to achieve an improvement of 75-100% on data access speeds. I was awarded as the **2013 Employee of the Year** (across 4500 employees in India) for this project.

ROHITS & CO. (INDIA)

Freelance Software Engineer

JUL 2011 - JAN 2013

Developed a desktop app to automate 15+ ERP workflows for SMBs, reducing process time from 30 days to 15 minutes.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

2015 - 2016

Candidate for MS in Robotics (Major – Artificial Intelligence)

GPA - 4.0 (on 4)

- A+ grade for a distributed mini-Google search engine (based on the PageRank algorithm) over 1M crawled pages
- 3 awards at PennApps world's largest hackathon 2nd Prize (2015), 2nd Prize (2016), Best Entrepreneurial Hack (2016)
- President for the Engineering Masters Advisory Board (EMAB) acting as a liaison between graduate students and the dean
- As a Research Assistant for Prof. Lyle Ungar developed an interactive Google map to display psychological trait differences in public Tweets for the World Well-Being Project (WWBP)

JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

2008 - 2013

Dual Degree BS (Computer Science) & MBA (HR)

MBA GPA - 8.9 | BS GPA - 8.5 (on 10)

- 2nd rank (out of 150)
- A+ grade for thesis project on Sign Language to Voice Conversion Gloves
- Government of India scholarship for academic excellence (for 5 years from 2008 2013)

SKILLS

- Product Management Customer Discovery, Feature Prioritization, Roadmaps, GTM and Pricing Strategies
- Full-Stack Development & Cloud Architecture Java, JS, SQL, AngularJS, Ionic, Cordova, React, NodeJS, Git, AWS
- Data & Analytics Python, Tableau, PowerBI
- Sales & Marketing Streak, Zoho, Hubspot, MailChimp
- UI/UX Photoshop, Inkscape
- Exceptional interpersonal and communication (written, verbal and presentation) skills
- Strong problem solving, negotiating, conflict resolution and decision-making skills

PATENTS & PUBLICATIONS

Visualization of Key Performance Indicator Dependencies (US)
 Optimization Using Statistical Estimation (US/EU)
 Virtual Split Dictionary for Search Optimization (US)
 Improved Expression of Breastmilk via Automated Methods (US)
 Multi-Dimensional Visual Analytics for Industries (US/India)
 Jun 2016 (Filed)
 Sep 2015 (Filed)

In-Memory DB Optimization Using Statistical Estimation (IEEE CCEM 2015)
 A Cost-Effective Sign Language to Voice Emulation System (IEEE IC3 2015)
 Aug 2015 (Published)